Come on,Joey!
喬伊，快說啦
I told you everything I knew last night.
我知道的部分昨晚都告訴你了
It's not that big a deal. So they're doing it.
摩妮卡和錢德搞在一起又怎樣
I cannot believe you would say that!
你居然這麼說
Sorry. Monica and Chandler are "making love."
抱歉 摩妮卡和錢德在「做愛」
No,I mean,come on. This is a huge deal!
不是啦，我是說這是大事耶
I need more details. Who initiated the first kiss?
我想知道細節 是誰先吻誰的？
I don't know.
不知
God,I just can't imagine Chandler being romantic.
我無法想像錢德浪漫的樣子
Is he romantic with her?
他跟她在一起時浪漫嗎？
I don't know.
不知
Are they in love?
他們相愛嗎？
I don't know.
不知
You don't know anything.
你什麼都不知道
I know one thing. What？
我知道一件事 什麼事？
They did it right there.
他們在這張沙發上做過
The One With Chandler's Work Laugh
本集播出：「瑞秋知道了」
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
（中央咖啡館）
Ross.
羅斯
Could I have a scone, please?
阿甘，給我一個英式鬆餅
-Want to hear some good news? -ls somebody else gonna give it to us?
想聽好消息嗎？ 有別人要說嗎？
Because you certainly don't seem like you have any.
你不像有好消息的樣子
No,I do. Someone I know is getting married.
不，我有 我認識的某人要結婚了
Weddings are happy occasions. Oh,it's my ex-wife,Emily!
婚禮是最開心的場合 對了，那人是我的前妻艾蜜莉
Sorry,man.
什麼？ 怎麼會這樣
-Here's your scone. -Thanks.
你的英式鬆餅 謝謝
Stupid British snack food!
什麼白癡英國點心！
Did they teach you that in anger management class?
那是情緒管理課教的嗎？
You know what might help you deal with it? Think it this way.
我有個辦法，你就這麼想
You two are in the past. You can't be mad about the past.
你和艾蜜莉已經過去了 你不能對過去的事生氣
Are you still mad about, you know, the Louisiana Purchase?
你還氣我們跟法國買土地嗎？
Nobody's mad about that.
菲比，沒有人在氣那個
Exactly! Because it's in the past.
沒錯，因為已經過去了
Anybody going to eat that?
那個有人要吃嗎？
Look at us all dressed up for the party. What are we celebrating?
我們盛裝參加公司宴會耶 是在慶祝什麼？
We had a lot of liquor left over from Christmas.
聖誕晚會剩了不少酒
Our friends aren't here. We can be a real couple. We don't have to hide.
真好，這裡沒有我們的朋友 我們可以公開，不必躲躲藏藏
I know. I can do this.
沒錯，我可以這樣
And I can do this.
而我可以這樣
We can't do that.
我們不能那樣
Hey,Bing!
賓
Who's the pretty lady, and what is she doing with you?
這位美女是誰 怎麼跟你在一起？
I asked myself that very question,sir. This is Monica.
我也這樣問自己 這是摩妮卡
My boss,Doug.
我上司道格
-This is Monica. -Hi.
道格，這是摩妮卡
-This is my wife,Kara. -Nice to meet you.
幸會 這是我老婆卡拉 很高興認識你… 賓
Did you hear about the new law firm working for us?
公司找了新法律顧問公司 是嗎？
Dickem,Stickem & Run.
杜塔、片達、豪伊事務所 （堵他，騙他，好耶）
Let's go drink our body weight.
我們去喝個痛快
What was that? What？
那是什麼？ 什麼？
That noise you made?
你剛才發出的聲音
Oh,my work laugh.
那是我的工作笑
Your work laugh?
你的工作笑？
If you're going to survive this party, come up with one too.
相信我，想熬過這場派對 你也得編出一個來
All right. Check me out.
好，看我的 好
He says,"$30,Father. Same as in town."
…30塊錢，跟城裡一樣
Everybody at work loved you last night.
昨晚公司的人都好喜歡你
And they like me more just because I was with you.
真的？ 而且他們因為你而更喜歡我
You repaired the damage from when they met Joey.
你彌補了不少喬伊造成的傷害
Doug wants to play tennis. He never talks to me outside of work.
道格還找我們打網球 他出了公司還沒理過我
Except for that time at that strip club.
除了在脫衣舞夜總會那次
Strip church.
脫衣舞教堂
-I'll go find a racket. -I thought you had one.
我要去找一支球拍 你不是有一支？
I used to,but then Joey thought it'd be fun to go hit rocks...
後來被喬伊拿去中央公園 對著石頭打…
...at bigger rocks.
大石頭
Do you have a tennis racket?
瑞秋，你有網球拍嗎？
I lent it to Joey,and I've never gotten it back.
我借給喬伊就沒拿回來過
Good luck with that.
祝你好運
What's up?
你好嗎？
Why are you here? I thought you had inventory.
你怎麼來了？今天不是要盤點
I do,but I decided I'd take a long lunch...
沒錯，但我決定午休久一點
...and spend some time with my friend Monica.
陪陪我的朋友摩妮卡
You know,I feel like we don't talk anymore.
我們現在都不談心了
How are you?
你好嗎？
What is new with you?
有什麼新變化？
Not much. Work's good.
不多，工作很順利
We don't have to talk about work. Talk about anything.
我們不必聊工作 什麼都可以聊
好吧…
You know what?
這樣吧
Let's talk about relationships.
我們來聊感情的事
What's going on?
好，你最近怎樣？
Nothing.
沒人追
You go.
該你
There was this guy at the bank that I thought was cute.
我原本覺得銀行有一個人很帥
But I don't anymore.
現在不覺得了
That's juicy.
真精彩
You know what? I actually do have a lot of work to do.
不過我確實很忙
You're sure there's just not anything else?
你確定沒別的了？
I'm sure. Is there something you want to talk to me about?
確定，你有什麼事想說嗎？
No!
沒有
If there was,I wouldn't tell you.
好吧，有也不告訴你
Then what happened?
好，然後呢？
You'll get your turn.
待會才輪到你
-Hey,Phoebe. What's going on? -Nothing.
菲比，在幹什麼？ 沒什麼
This is not over.
待會再繼續
No,no,no!
糟糕 怎麼了？
I was up all night writing this nasty letter to Emily.
我熬了一整晚寫信罵艾蜜莉
It was perfect, and now it's all covered in....
原本寫得很好，現在沾滿了…
Actually,thanks!
謝了
All right! Ready to go to the movies?
可以去看電影了嗎？
Actually,I think I'll skip it.
我想我不去了
Really?
你不去？
I'll read my book. I just want to be alone right now.
對，我要留下來看書 我現在只想靜一靜
Sure you don't want to?
你真的不去？
Tom Hanks,Meg Ryan. They get mail and stuff.
湯姆漢克斯，梅格萊恩 寫信什麼的
That's okay,Joe.
我還是不去了
Let's go, Phoebe.
好吧，菲比我們走
好惡
賓
Game!
贏了
I got to tell you,that partner of yours is a real tiger.
說真的，你的搭檔真是快狠準
Are you all right?
你還好嗎？
We'll just get a little sip of water.
我們喝口水
Am I on fire today or what?
我今天很猛吧？
Those birds are browned, basted and ready to be carved.
那兩支肉雞已經烤好 等著被切來吃了
Okay,easy,Martina.
別激動，網球名將
I think we should let them win the next game.
我覺得下一場應該讓他們贏
I'm sorry,I don't understand what you just said.
對不起，你剛說的話我聽不懂
Let them win one.
讓他們贏一場
Are you crazy? We own those two. Look at them!
你瘋了嗎？他們任我們宰割
He can't even breathe, and she's popping pills.
你看他們 他喘不過氣來，她在吃藥
You're not giving them a chance.
你根本不給他們機會
They have rackets.
他們有球拍不是嗎？
We'll make this the last game.
賓，我想打完這場就收了
Yes,sir. Put me out of my misery.
暸解，我求之不得
Are you sure you never played pro?
你真的沒打過職業？
Please let them win.
拜託讓他們贏
I'll take it down to 95%, but that's the best I can do.
我頂多只能把戰力降到95%
-Missed it! -I got it!
糟糕，漏掉了 我來
Nice shot.
好球
I got it!
我來
Long!
出界
I can't believe you let them win.
你居然讓他們贏
Well,at least you hid your feelings well about it.
至少你把不爽掩飾得很好
I was frustrated.
我很沮喪
It's my racket.
這是我的球拍
Frustrated with you!
是你讓我沮喪
If we hadn't lost,they would never have invited us to dinner tomorrow.
如果沒輸那場球 他們也不會找我們明天去吃飯
What bothers me...
我最困擾的是
...is how different you act around them.
你在他們身邊整個人都變了
The throwing the tennis games, the fake laugh...
故意輸球，工作笑
...the "See you later,Bing!" "Not if I see you first,Doug!"
「回頭見，賓」 「不回頭就不見」
Listen,I don't sound like some crazed, drunken pirate.
我哪有笑得像喝醉的海盜
I know you don't, but "work Chandler" does.
你沒有，但工作的錢德有
I don't like work Chandler. The guy's a suck-up.
我不喜歡工作的錢德 那傢伙是個狗腿
Because you said that...
因為你這些話
...I'm not putting out tonight!
我晚上不跟你玩了
Something's wrong. My brother doesn't stay out all night.
絕對有問題 我哥從來不徹夜不歸
Maybe we should check the trash chute.
也許應該去看看垃圾槽
Ross couldn't fit down the trash chute.
羅斯擠不進垃圾槽
That's right. He almost could.
沒錯，就差那麼一點點
Which is exactly how I got stuck there.
所以我之前卡住過
Oh,my God!
他回來了 天哪
Where the hell have you been?
你死哪去了？
Just,you know,out.
就是去外面了
Oh,out! God,I don't know why we didn't think to check there.
外面，天哪 我們怎麼沒去那裡找
What were you doing?
你都在做什麼？
I went to a bar,and then...
我先去喝酒，然後...
...I just walked around for a while.
...就隨便走了走
You walked around all night in the city by yourself?
你整夜一個人在外面亂晃？
He hooked up!
他嘿咻了
He hooked up.
他跟某人嘿咻了
I don't have to answer your questions. I'm a big boy.
我不必回答你們的問題 我是個大人
I can do what I want.
愛怎樣就怎樣
He hooked up!
他嘿咻了
Tell us about her!
聊聊她嘛
Ross,you left your scarf
羅斯，你把圍巾掉在…
Hey,you guys.
你們好
I know what you all are thinking, but Chandler is in Yemen.
好，我知道你們在想什麼 但錢德在葉門
I'm a young woman. I have needs. I can't wait forever.
我還年輕，我有需求 我不能等一輩子
Yeah,that's what I was thinking.
我也是這麼想的
So I'm asking you,please, just take a moment before you judge me.
所以我求求你們 在批評我之前先想一下
Nobody's judging you.
沒有人在批評你
Mr. Right-place-at-the-right-time...
你，天時地利人和先生
...call me.
跟我聯絡
So I guess you finished your book.
看來你的書看完了
Had some time on our hands,did we?
有點閒是吧？
I know what you guys are going to say.
我知道你們要說什麼…
You two would have very hairy children.
你們的孩子會毛茸茸的
I didn't know you'd say that.
我不知道你會說那個
Ross! Janice?
羅斯，珍妮絲耶？
All right. Hold on,hold on.
等一下…
This is Ross.
這是羅斯
He's our friend. He obviously went crazy.
他是我們的朋友 他顯然是瘋了
He obviously lost his mind.
腦筋秀逗了
Look,it's not that crazy. Okay?
沒那麼誇張，好嗎？
But it's Janice! I mean,she's...
但是珍妮絲耶 她是…
...Janice!
...珍妮絲耶
How drunk were you?
你醉得太離譜了
Janice and I have a lot in common.
珍妮絲和我有很多共同點
We've both been divorced. We both have kids.
我們都離過婚，我們都有小孩
Are you going to see her again?
你真的要再見她？
-Don't put ideas in his head! -I will see her.
菲比，別影響他 我確實要再見她
Damn it,Phoebe!
你看啦
I have to tell you something that I've never admitted.
我要說出一件我沒坦承過的事
In high school,I made out with James even though I knew you liked him.
高中時 我知道你喜歡詹姆法洛 但還是跟他上了床
That feels so good to get off my chest. Okay,you go.
哇，說出來的感覺真好 好，該你了
My turn? What are you talking about?
該我了？什麼意思？
I know about you and Chandler.
摩妮卡，我知道你和錢德的事
I overheard you on the phone the other day.
什麼？ 我那天聽到你們在講電話
You said, "I'll tell Rachel I'm doing laundry for a couple of hours."
你說「我會告訴瑞秋」 「我要花兩個小時洗衣服」
And he said, "Laundry? Is that my new nickname?"
他說「洗衣服？」 「那是我的新綽號嗎？」
And you said:
然後你說
"You know what your nickname is, Mr. Big."
「不是」 「你明知你的綽號是大雕」
You're writing yourself a little play there,Rach.
原來你正在寫劇本
Let me know how it turns out.
記得把結局告訴我
I wouldn't know,because I got so freaked out I hung up the phone.
我不知道 因為我嚇到把電話掛掉了
Well,if you had kept listening...
如果你聽完
...you would have heard me call him Mister...
你會聽到我是叫他大…
...Bigot.
碉堡
Mr. Bigot.
什麼？ 大碉堡
He tells the most racist jokes.
他喜歡講碉堡的笑話
All right. So that's it.
好，所以就這樣
There's nothing going on between you and Chandler?
你是說你和錢德之間沒什麼
Me and Chandler?
我和錢德？
Put your $20 down.
拿出20元來
First one to find the tasty treat wins,okay?
先找到零食的贏，好嗎？
All right,let's get the contestants out of their isolation booths.
好，請參賽者從休息室出場
And they're off!
它們出場了
Get your foot off my contestant! Judge?
別擋住我的參賽者，裁判
Judge rules,no violation.
裁判判定沒有違規
你們好
It's so weird to say this, but I just had a great date with Janice.
說也奇怪 我今天跟珍妮絲過得很開心
-What? -Are you serious?
什麼？ 真的假的？
I opened up to her about all the stuff that's been happening to me.
沒錯，我跟她訴說近來的慘事
I mean,I talked for hours.
我說了好幾個小時
It is amazing...
這種感覺真好
...to have someone give you such focused attention.
有人能專心聽你傾訴
You don't need Janice for that. You've got us.
那你何必找她，你有我們
The duck gets the Nutter Butter!
鴨子找到花生醬餅乾了 不
That's not a Nutter Butter. That's an old won ton!
那不是花生醬餅乾 那是一顆餛飩
Judge rules...
裁判判定：
...Nutter Butter.
是花生醬餅乾
Tough call.
真難判 是啊
Seriously,I strongly believe that we should support President Clinton...
但我們應該支持柯林頓總統
...and her husband,Bill.
和她的老公比爾
How do you like your coffee?
你們的咖啡要怎麼上？
-None for me. -A little sugar.
我不要，謝謝 我要一點點糖
I'll have Monica stick her finger in it. That will sweeten it up.
那就讓摩妮卡把指頭伸進去 應該就會甜了
-That laugh doesn't give you a headache? -You get used to it.
你那樣笑怎麼不會頭痛？ 久了就習慣了
I don't think that I can.
我不覺得我會習慣
This will be it for me on the work things.
我以後就不甩這套了
I laugh at my boss's jokes. What's the big deal?
老闆說笑我就笑，這有什麼嗎
I'd rather not be with this work-weasel guy...
我幹嘛要陪一個沒尊嚴的馬屁精
...when I can be with my boyfriend, who I actually respect.
如果能跟我尊敬的男友在一起
I got to apologize for Kara's coffee. I'd feel sorry for it in a fight.
我得為卡拉煮的咖啡道歉 如果它去打架
It's not strong enough to defend itself.
連自己都保護不了
Hear what I said?
你聽到我的話了嗎？
What?
什麼？
It's a joke. What's the matter with you?
那個笑話啊，你是怎麼了？
Well,I just didn't think it was funny,sir.
我只是覺得不好笑
Excuse me?
你說什麼？
-Well,I just -Honey?
我只是… 親愛的
I just don't think you understood the joke.
我覺得你沒聽懂
Really?
是嗎？
I mean,it was really funny. I just don't think that you got it.
很好笑耶，你一定是沒聽懂
You see,Kara's coffee is weak-tasting.
卡拉煮的咖啡很稀
But what Doug did was imply that it was weak physically.
但道格是在暗示它很虛弱
-You get it now,honey? -I think I do!
現在你懂了嗎？ 我懂了
-Thank you,Monica. -I thought you could use the help.
謝謝你 我覺得你需要解釋
Coffee in a fight!
咖啡打架
You mind if I read my comic books in here?
瑞秋，我可以在這裡看漫畫嗎
Sure. Why?
當然可以，怎麼了？
Chandler and Monica are over there. It's kind of hard to concentrate.
錢德和摩妮卡在一起 我很難專心
She just called and said she was going to be working late.
什麼？她剛打來說她要加班
She keeps lying to me.
她一直騙我
That's it! I'm going over there and confronting them right now.
夠了，我現在就過去揭穿他們
Panty raid.
去找小褲褲！
All right,so you're telling me that I have to tell racist jokes now?
所以我得講碉堡的笑話？
I'm just not very good at this.
對不起，我不太會圓謊
I'm a terrible liar. I hate having to lie to Rachel.
我很不會騙人 我又很討厭騙瑞秋
-But we're not ready to tell yet. -I know.
但我們還不能公開 我知道，只是…
Ever since high school, Rachel was the one person that I told everything to.
從高中起我什麼事都告訴瑞秋
I miss that so much now.
我好懷念那種感覺
She's my best friend.
她是我最要好的朋友
喬伊？
Oh,my God,Rachel!
天哪，瑞秋
What are you doing here?
你怎麼跑來這裡？
Well,I actually came over here to borrow this lamp...
我是…我來借這盞燈
...to look at my books.
好看書...
You know,see them a little better.
看得清楚一點
Okay,great.
太好了
Well,what I was doing in Chandler's room is that...
我在錢德的房間裡是因為…
...I was cleaning it.
我在幫忙打掃
He pays me to clean it.
他付錢請我打掃
What a great way to make some extra pocket money.
真是個賺零用錢的好辦法
When I said to you earlier that I was at work...
之前我說要加班
...I'm at my new work.
...是指我的新工作
Good enough. Right?
真不錯，對吧？
I'll go look at my books.
好，那…我要去看書了
Go get back to my new job.
好，我得去忙我的新工作了
好
Congratulations on your new job!
恭喜你找到這份工作
Man,she is really gullible.
天哪，她可真好騙
-Here you go. -Thanks.
你們的咖啡 謝謝
-Actually,I should get going. -You're sure?
其實我該走了 你確定？
I can stay out as late as you want.
你想留多晚我都奉陪
I told you I'm on sabbatical from work
我說過我為什麼休長假吧？
Yes,yes. You did.
對，你說過
-Oh,man! -What is wrong now?
又怎麼了？
This isn't what I ordered.
我不是點的這個
Man! Can't anything go right in my life?
我的人生就不能順利一點嗎？
First,my marriage falls apart, and then
先是我的婚姻破裂，然後…
I know!
我知道！
You lose your apartment, you lose your job...
然後你被趕出你家 你的工作沒了
...your ex-wife gets married so fast! And now the coffee!
你的前妻很快就再婚 現在咖啡又錯了
-We need to talk. -Okay.
我們得談一談 好
-Sometimes I feel -No,no,don't.
有時我覺得… 不…
I'm going to talk.
是我要說
I believe...
我認為
...that the sun has set...
我們的美好時光
...on our day in the sun.
已經日落了
You're a very sweet person,Ross.
什麼？ 你是個很好的人
Unfortunately...
只是...
...I just don't think I can take another second of you whining!
我沒辦法再聽你哀下去了
Let me make sure I'm hearing this right.
我跟你確認一下
You're ending this with me because...
你要跟我結束 因為...
...I'm too whiny?
...我太會發牢騷？
So you're saying...
你是說
...I've become so whiny...
...我是這麼地愛發牢騷...
...that l...
...我...
...annoy you...
...讓你覺得很煩...
...Janice.
...珍妮絲…
Well,yeah!
沒錯
Oh,my God!
我…的…天哪
Will you be okay?
你不要緊吧？
I am now.
現在不要緊了
I guess that's two out of three...
已經兩人出局了…
...Joey!
...喬伊
-Dude,we got to talk. -Okay.
我們得談一談 好
I wanted to tell you something before you heard it from someone else.
我只是想趁你聽說之前告訴你
I hope this isn't too weird,but...
希望不會太奇怪
...I had a thing with Janice.
我最近跟珍妮絲交往過
You're not mad?
你不生氣？
Why would I be mad?
我幹嘛生氣？
Because there's certain rules about this kind of stuff.
因為這種事有它的道義在
You don't fool around with your friends' ex-girlfriends...
不能追朋友的舊情人
...or possible girlfriends or girls they're related to.
心上人 或是有親屬關係的人
I am mad.
我很生氣
But you know, I'm going to forgive you.
但是你知道嗎？我要原諒你
Because that's what friends do.
因為那樣才叫兄弟
They forgive their friends when they do everything you just said.
他們會原諒朋友 犯了你念的那串禁忌
Thank you.
謝謝
But I want you to remember...
不過我要你記住...
...that I forgave you.
...我原諒了你
I also want you to remember that I let you live here rent-free.
好 我還要你記住我免費收留你
All right.
好
And I want you to remember that I gave you...
我還要你記住我送你...
...twenty-seven dollars.
...27塊錢
No strings attached!
無條件奉送
If you can't remember that...
要是你記不住
...we should write it down. Let's write it down!
我們應該寫下來… 我們寫下來吧